<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on The Danger Zone</title>
    <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/tags/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on The Danger Zone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 05:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://therealmjp.github.io/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Retro Development: SNES Edition</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/adventures-in-retro-development-snes-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 05:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/adventures-in-retro-development-snes-edition/</guid>
      <description>When I was growing up, the SNES was easily my favorite console. How could it not be, with top-tier games like Super Metroid and Mega Man X available? I had always wanted to learn how to program for the SNES so that I could develop my own silly games for the hardware that ran my favorite games as a kid. I decided to use this past holiday break as an excuse to finally get started, and I had a great time doing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update For My Shadow Sample Update</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/update-for-my-shadow-sample-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/update-for-my-shadow-sample-update/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was contacted by Christoph Peters (one of the authors of Moment Shadow Mapping) regarding a blog post where I compared EVSM to MSM using my sample app. He noticed that I was incorrectly clamping the maximum exponential warp to 10.0 for the 16-bit variant of EVSM, which can result in values that are greater than what can be stored in a 16-bit floating point texture. Doing this has 2 effects: it causes incorrect results during filtering (clamping the moments can lead to negative variance, causing a reconstruction that resembles a step function), and it reduces the amount of light bleeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stairway To (Programmable Sample Point) Heaven</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/programmable-sample-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 03:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/programmable-sample-points/</guid>
      <description>What Is and Should Never Be Historically, the sub-pixel location of MSAA sample points was totally out of your control as a programmer. Typically the hardware used rotated grid patterns such as this one, which were fixed for every pixel in your render target. For FEATURE_LEVEL_10_1, D3D added the concept of standard sample patterns that were required to be supported by the hardware. These were nice, in that you could specify the appropriate quality level and know exactly where the samples would be located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIGGRAPH Follow-Up: 2015 Edition</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/siggraph-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 05:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/siggraph-2015/</guid>
      <description>SIGGRAPH 2015 wrapped up just a few days ago, and it really was fantastic this year! There was tons of great content, and I got a chance to meet up with some of best graphics programmers in the industry. I wanted to thank anyone that came to my talk at Advances in Real-Time Rendering, as well as anyone who came to our talk at the Physically Based Shading course. It&amp;rsquo;s always awesome to see so many people interested in the latest rendering technology, and the other presenters really knocked it out of the park in both courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Special Thanks</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/some-special-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 08:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/some-special-thanks/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, a little game called The Order: 1886 finally hit store shelves. Its release marks the culmination of my past 4 years at Ready At Dawn, which were largely devoted to developing the core rendering and engine technology that was ultimately used for the game. It&amp;rsquo;s also a major milestone for me personally, as it&amp;rsquo;s the first project that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on full-time from start to finish. I&amp;rsquo;m of course immensely proud of what our team has managed to accomplish, and I feel tremendously lucky to go to work every day with such a talented and dedicated group of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come see me talk at GDC 2014</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/come-see-me-talk-at-gdc-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 06:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/come-see-me-talk-at-gdc-2014/</guid>
      <description>Myself and fellow lead graphics programmer David Neubelt will be at GDC next week, talking about the rendering technology behind The Order: 1886. Unfortunately the talk came together a bit late, and so it initially started from the talk that we gave back at SIGGRAPH at last year (which is why it has the same title). However we don&amp;rsquo;t want to just rehash the same material, so we&amp;rsquo;ve added tons of new slides and revamped the old ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve been working on for the past 2 years</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/what-ive-been-working-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 07:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/what-ive-been-working-on/</guid>
      <description>The announce trailer for Ready At Dawn&amp;rsquo;s latest project was shown during Sony&amp;rsquo;s E3 press conference yesterday, but if you missed it you can watch it here. There&amp;rsquo;s also a few full-res screenshots available here, with less compress-o-vision. It feels really good to finally be able to tell people what game I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, and that we&amp;rsquo;re making a PS4 title. I&amp;rsquo;m also insanely proud of the trailer itself, as well as the in-house tech we&amp;rsquo;ve developed that made it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a job?</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/looking-for-a-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 22:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/looking-for-a-job/</guid>
      <description>My company, Ready At Dawn Studios, is hiring pretty much across the board. Our jobs page has the full details, but the gist of it is that we&amp;rsquo;re working on a new AAA IP for a next-generation home console. I can&amp;rsquo;t really say more than that about the project, but I will say that we&amp;rsquo;re doing some *really* exciting work in terms of graphics. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, send your resume to jobs[at]readyatdawn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Profiling in DX11 with Queries</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/profiling-in-dx11-with-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 08:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/profiling-in-dx11-with-queries/</guid>
      <description>For profiling GPU performance on the PC, there aren&amp;rsquo;t too many options. AMD&amp;rsquo;s GPU PerfStudio and Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s Parallel Nsight can be pretty handy due to their ability to query hardware performance counters and display the data, but they only work on each vendor&amp;rsquo;s respective hardware. You also might want to integrate some GPU performance numbers into your own internal profiling systems, in which case those tools aren&amp;rsquo;t going to be of much use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undo and Redo: Take 2</title>
      <link>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/undo-and-redo-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 19:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://therealmjp.github.io/posts/undo-and-redo-take-2/</guid>
      <description>Please excuse the rhyming in the title&amp;hellip;sometimes I just can&amp;rsquo;t help myself. It&amp;rsquo;s a problem.
A few weeks ago I started working on a super-duper-secret project (to be revealed soon), a big part of which was a new editor. Since I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of guy who gets all worked up about having proper undo and redo support, I took the opportunity to make it an up-front part of my design rather than just shoving it in afterwords.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>